[Music]
Okay,
no, what do they do? What is next?
Jacqueline. So,
evaluator policy.
[Music]
Of terminology inherited from
legacy terminology. So, this is infinite
from control theories. So, no, I want to have no
control. I have evaluation and have control.
Right, so I have evaluation. I have done data. So, yes,
you do, I do control.
Very simple
project, please, I don't have
convergence. Right, so I just
evaluated on a project tree.
Valuation on a transaction. If you
start from state, this is just running the
transaction multiple times and take the
average and used value on the status. Right,
guarantee date. This value comes to computer. This is an true value
on the status inside the policy. Okay,
some approximation of data, but I'm happy, stop there. Right,
this is one think about
generalize policy. Edit mention. Right, so you don't have to
value it. You have to find the
true value of an state. Also,
you can find the approximate value on the  d
state right you can cup going and her was
essential what bill do her so they take an
state they take some sample from d state
right and give find the value and give you
can and try you be greedy with respect to
d qualify function okay so
other problem
method because they don't have any of the concrete and
they don't need any of the concrete and k with sample
model right but no you are telling me just you
start expression you be greedy I can't do they get already
no hot today just look at
d values ​​of concrete action I don't need you to
look at so when I do
control I use the k
function
start from her anything okay
and give more fundamental questions date okay
action was suggested in policy
you turn so date is should this is you get in all
kinds of problems maybe because you draw a
disproportionately larger number of
samples from
actions corresponding to you pipe
such post actions that are not corresponding
So it turns out
conditions in which convergence note be guaranteed
right so you bill get some they are dance only have you know I want
evaluate all sc
pads right only given I can do Apollo's
improvement right only evaluate actions
corresponding to you five given I can do policy
improvement right so turns out date I bill be
proportionately valuing actions
corresponding to you by right four they never do this right
sample and I used only per
updating d value
which d sample
update d value of k s1 a1 I need you
start from s1
and give water
you are doing large number of samples about one
think turn of d convergence okay it's a little long
time and d convergence was d open
of d textbook and they actually say in
d textbook it is tiller open question because it was
written in 97 and it was proven
only in 2002 date it not converge
and  You do date and they have to actually know on
you d cat d answer little key because with
introduction this date so you are getting to me
samples of one think date on d rate of
convergence per just date as c match faster than as one a
one way match faster than author
kids of things
one probably convergence face only you him the
first date
first date and first action
what by you do when i can actually it only by
red i cant do polls
improvement on date having
outside work
ok in nature work but you can guarantee
conversion so per guarantee conversion
state so no one from date you have to do it only
on initial state your
exploring starch becomes more
important
so date you can get d good estimate on date
and so you cant be creative particular state if
unless you have taken at least a
good fraction of d actions from d state
trade and try to estimate  nothing so
welcome ok
exploring starters right again it's not
clear whether this screen is called
absol on soft policy
right so whenever i say do an policy
improvement i don't give you an greedy
policy
date is mostly greedy right so most of the
probability bill is given to one action and some
of the probability bill gets distributed to
jo d actions
ok sir start
please jo d actions from jo d status
note just see p action corresponding sample
jo d action film jo d status so this is
tomorrow absol on soft policy
[music]
and it's absorbed it means date every
action is being
taken from every state
right so uniform random policy
rate absol on greedy execution of an
policy it is also absol on soft policy
and soft policy
would be some per some app on policy
[music]
close it bill meet with the true value and
guarantee anything
this is very simple set  Forward thinking right
and depends on d number of samples and
it's so afraid and rates of convergence set you
can establish based on the number of
samples
probability if
you new the transaction probability
and d things you are you jump apply
concentration
more like textbook exercise application of
but a little complicated because d
distribution your sampling from
distribution dat roll in your in this
how it me fine right
so absol on soft policies so no d
question becomes dat is they should you an
policy iteration conversion right about dat is
searching dat you are greedy with respect to
d previous policies value function no I am
saying don't be great be absol on
soft with respect to d previous
value and bill this converge
and so what you what
okay
and optimal apps of policy were d
highest probability bill b living tu d
after an election
you have an  Very specific way of generating
web policy from the
previous iteration something
or else other questions on this
topic
importance
of policy right when I am not
exploring starters right and
I am not really getting what I want right
and actually solving something else if
you want valuable
deterministic policy starters
deterministic flooring starters and I can't do
exploration of d status and
give estimate d value of d policy
what should give d value to other policy
date you ask
policies are evaluating from d policy
d time using p behaving so such
kids of method and called
[music]
of policy method so what ever you have talk about so for
called on policies method same because
d sample are generated by d
policies which I am trying table
it's each and every in both cases in d samples are
being generated it with  Respect your
policies
method and sample bill generated in
different policies
simple think right so essentially so what I am
looking at is this I am I want you
compute expectation
's sum function
[music]
where x is
sample from
some distribution p
[music]
Jay Roshan
sample from
some distribution p so this is
expectation date I want an computer
distribution
access you p okay but I have some sort of
sampling x
they are here right so give me what bill do so I
bill you speak and ask me you give me
next I bill see
three four eight three nine it is telling
me numbers like this know what I do is I
bill play in three four eight nine whatever date
in you f of x I bill add up which d
values ​​of fc/n and bill give you know it so I how
I approximate this is
essentially was
sample from know what I don't something
outcomes okay but you can only tell  me things
according to you you are
going you give me number
lot of times in d first sequence of
number
8 and 9 our more right so no what I do yes I am
saying date a I don't have b but I have some other
distribution
[music]
expectation is a perfect
weighted with ratio of d property
you on every sample you give me i bill
fixed right on computer and also
multiply it with this ratio of you and
give add up everything and take d average i
bill give me d average of i fixed if d
samples per round according to you
everyday
importance
of piece is very big and few small give d
importance bill is very very big on d
tax so fair files is very small give
so it's fine thank you if x you will be more
frequent inside give I want you to give it a
lower weight when I completed
expectation  events happen you will be less
frequent and k give repeat I want you to give it
more weight and and expectation so this voice
call importance weighting and
important weight sorry important factor and
importance weight
of sampling you determine d expectations is called
other gasses
important sample you are not able to
sample from p
and not able to draw samples from p e x
ected ra samples from k can you think I have to find the serious serious
but serious
you computer actually simulate samples
from k and from p i right so insect
cases where they are talking about I have
return
mistake policy and I have an policy whether
this is hard but me you execute I have some
random behavior policy right so use d
random behavior policy
bill wickham I
live TV
from d rejectively right k bill b
policies
wickham zero and square other
x per wich
zero
assure date you access non  Other Pixis on Zero
[Music]
And Another Way of Generating Apps
Saying They Should Insure Date Every action has at
list some small applicability on the
probability of being pik So dat way per
whatever be the policy dat you want estimate
value on this it is never become zero whenever
you want so this it is also dat this can
suffer from instability if
you are trying to do this clear
pik is non zero but case is close to zero
importance is very very
large it is
of d ratio bill be
normalized important
[Music]
of this but
this turns out have higher bs and dat
bill have variance so for every sample dat you
draw it can fluctuate remember every which it is
note every sample and give limit very
convergent you d se answer
no but so this weight this normalized
important sampling is considered but
in practice  Because it's a lot more stable
okay so that's it you deposit sampling I'm going to
stop today an cup d
importance sampling in your mind when
you come to your class I
bill tel you ho you him important sampling
you do of policy level
okay bill k out exactly what is d p
and what is d when date they have you him but
importance complete okay and date bill take me
about 15 minutes and after date bill ko you
after six tha bill b inside chapter 5 so
chapter 5 today
bill b small beat of chapter five left in
d next class and after date bill move you
six
[music]
[applause]